#### Contact

kuznetsov.eric@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erickuznetsov (LinkedIn) github.com/Caramel-Pudding (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

JavaScript React.js TypeScript

### Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

# Eric Kuznetsov

Senior Frontend Engineer @ Delivery Hero Berlin, Berlin, Germany

### Summary

My main goal is to always deliver a product of flawless quality that would give an equally good experience for the end-users, consuming it and for my fellow developing team, creating it. And I'm always wide open and eager for new ways to create this experience.

For the end-users, I adore delivering beautiful and simplistic interfaces. In my work, I'm passionate to observe challenges of any complexity from different angles, encompassing different aspects - performance, accessibility, reliability. Besides that, it's always desirable for me to reach out even further and collaborate not only to get the job done but to do it excellently.

For my fellow developing team, I'm always ready to share with the best of my experience and knowledge. Making the development process painless is one of my main focuses, which I achieve by different means - bringing automation, code quality tools, and improving team communication.

## Experience

Delivery Hero 3 years 8 months

Senior Software Engineer
January 2024 - Present (1 year 8 months)
Berlin, Germany

Software Engineer
January 2022 - January 2024 (2 years 1 month)
Berlin, Germany

Sberbank
Senior Frontend Developer
May 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 8 months)
St Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

The project I'm working on:

Client manager assistance system. Developing a toolbox for business clients' managers at the largest Russian bank.

Technologies we're using:

HTML/CSS, TypeScript, React, Redux, WebPack, PostCSS, CSS Modules, Jest, ESlint

Besides the usual work, I'm...

-Leading the development of side-projects and prototypes from scratch to release, allowing businesses to swiftly and seamlessly test hypotheses.

-Acting as a Build Engineer in an additional role, maintaining Jenkins-based infrastructure, automating CI/CD processes, and providing the team with fresh releases.

Sletat.ru Frontend Developer August 2019 - April 2020 (9 months) Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

The project I was working on:

Touristic service startup with a fast-paced development velocity. Creating various services for clients, business partners, and internal company employees.

Technologies we used:

HTML/CSS, TypeScript, React, MobX, WebPack, PostCSS, CSS Modules, Jest, ESlint, Sentry, StoryBook

Besides the usual work, I've...

- -Pushed the product forward through proactive team collaboration and advocating for ideas and business vision.
- -Proposed and implemented data visualization based on D3 charts which significantly improved UX and increased conversion.

-Integrated Code Quality tools like Prettier, Stylelint, and advanced ESlint config which remarkably increased code consistency and smoothed the codereview process which subsequently improved DX and delivery speed.

EPAM Systems
Frontend Developer
October 2017 - August 2019 (1 year 11 months)
Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

The project I was working on:

E-commerce for a global pharmaceutical company. Migrating from legacy ASP.NET to React. Also worked on smaller projects with a similar stack.

Technologies we used: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest, ESlint,

Besides the usual work, I've...

- -As part of an international team, I was presenting our product to the customer, providing transparency and demonstration.
- -Took mentoring responsibility, helping fresh students and interns to integrate into a company and their first projects.
- -Proactively cultivated internal IT community, participating in the organization of meet-ups, conferences, and a podcast.

### Education

Peter the Great St.Petersburg Polytechnic University Bachelor's degree, Information Technology · (2014 - 2018)